Now, let's look at the second question of interest.
现在我们来看一下第二个感兴趣的问题
That is, what does the data suggest about
编程训练营是否会对就业和工资有影响?
Again, let's read in the data and the necessary libraries.
同样地 先读入数据以及需要用到的库
In the case of our second question,
在第二个问题中
we were only interested in boot camp grads.
我们只对编程训练营的毕业生感兴趣
Let's narrow our dataset down to just those individuals.
所以只需要筛选出相关人员的数据
Looks like there's about 2,600 of them in this dataset.
看上去筛选出了 2600 多条数据
Many boot camps suggest that they're aimed at helping
很多编程训练营宣称
people who are underrepresented in the technical community.
他们旨在帮助那些在技术社区中被忽视的人
Let's take a look at some of those characteristics and see what shows up in our dataset.
我们来观察一下数据中的不同特征 看看能发现什么
Looking at gender, here's the breakdown of those different areas,
先来看性别 可以看到不同类别的占比
86 percent male, 11 percent female,
男性有 86% 女性有 11%
and the remaining three percent or so,
剩下的大概有 3%
a little less than three percent are in some,
不足 3% 这些其他类别加起来的占比
If we compare this to the gender breakdown of the non-boot camp grads,
如果与 not_bootcamp_df 的性别比例进行对比
we can see if they're really helping the underrepresented groups.
可以从中观察出编程训练营是否真的对 "弱势群体" 有帮助
As you can see, there is about a four percent larger group in the males,
如你所见 男性群体的比例增加了 4% 左右
and that basically directly comes from the female portion.
女性群体的比例同时减少了约 4%
So, there is a slight increase of females in boot camps than in the current industry.
也就是说 与业内相比 参与编程训练营的女性比例稍有增加
However, as far as the rest of the groups are concerned, it's about the same.
不过其他人群类别的差距则不是很大
Additionally, we could look at a breakdown by formal education.
此外 我们还可以看一下制式教育的分类占比
So, of those who were in the boot camp,
在参与过编程训练营的人群中
about 48 percent had a bachelor's degree before going in,
48% 的人具有学士学位
and 23 percent have a master's degree.
23% 的人具备硕士学位
And you can see the breakdown of some of these other things,
然后再来看下其他类别
even two percent have a doctoral degree,
甚至有 2% 的人有博士学位
and 1.6 percent have a professional degree.
1.6% 的人有专业学位
Pretty high in like a pretty large number of years and
在参加编程训练营之前 他们在传统教育体系里待的时间挺长的
And then, if we look at,
然后再来看一下
this is the people who are not in a boot camp,
没有参加过编程训练营的人
and we see the breakdown of them.
可以看到各类的比例
You can see that fewer of them have a bachelor's degree,
拥有学士学位的人比例变少了
about the same have a master's degree,
硕士学位的比例差不多
about the same have some college,
大学学历的比例也差不多
about the same for a PhD,
博士学位也是
and for a professional degree.
以及专业学位
So, it looks like they're polling more people with bachelor's degrees.
这样看上去 训练营似乎招收了更多拥有学士学位的人群
So, that's kind of interesting.
有点意思
There's like six percent increase of those individuals going into here.
因为这里的差距差不多有 6%
But it doesn't look like it's really changing the professional,
但是对于其他学位
doctoral, or masters degrees that much.
专业学位、硕士、博士 差距就没有那么大
People are just choosing another form of education that isn't a master's or
看来有些人在拿到学士学位之后 选择了其他的教育方式
PhD after getting a bachelor's according to this.
而没有选择继续攻读硕士或博士
More of them are getting a bachelor's and they're choosing one of those two routes.
更多的是获取学士学位 选择两种途径之一
Another interesting column that we could look at is basically how much time after
另一个有探索价值的问题是 参与训练营之后
the boot camp it takes for an individual to find a job.
花了多长时间找到工作
So, here's an interesting part about the boot camp.
这里又能发现一个很有趣的现象
Persona is that 46 percent of those individuals already had jobs,
46% 在参加训练营的时候就已经有工作了
11 percent got them immediately after graduating,
11% 的人训练营刚毕业就找到了工作
and then about 10 percent got jobs as developers before completing the program.
10% 在毕业前就找到了工作
So, that's, what is that?
一共是多少呢?
56, 64 percent have jobs before completing the program or right at graduation,
64% 的人在参加编程营过程中或一毕业就找到工作
or they already had them.
或者原本就有工作
And then 1-3 months afterwards,
大约有 9% 的人 在毕业 1 - 3 个月之内找到工作
and just under 10 percent still haven't had a job since completing the survey
有少于 10% 的人在完成调查问卷时还没有找到工作
which is kind of tough because you don't know if they just
这就有点难判断了 因为这些人有可能是刚毕业
graduated or maybe they graduated six months later,
也可能是已经毕业 6 个月了
or maybe it's been nine months or a year,
或者毕业 9 个月或一年了之类的
This status is kind of hard to read because you don't
所以这条信息不太好解读
know the time frame that those individuals are falling into.
因为你不知道应该将他们归于哪种时间范围
So, another interesting thing we could look at,
还有一个有趣的特征
is the salary breakdown of these individuals who came from boot camps.
参加训练营群体的工资情况
So here, I'll just build a histogram of the salary with 20 bins.
这里我创建了一个 20 个区间的直方图
And if we take a look at this,
观察这个图表
you can see that it's kind of all over the place.
你会发现什么情况都有
So, there's somebody up here makes $200,000 a year, and then,
有些人的年薪高达 20 万美元
it looks like there's a huge spike right here at the beginning
而另一边开始的位置 能看到一个峰值
which might be those individuals who are still searching for work,
很可能代表的是那些还在找工作的人
and then there's still just a huge spectrum.
然后可以看到中间的范围跨度很大
So, boot camps don't seem to be very consistent in
也就是说 参加训练营并不能保证工资一定处于某个区间
There are clearly other factors that are involved
除了是否参加过编程训练营
besides just whether or not someone went to a boot camp or not.
显然还存在很多其他与工资相关的因素
So, my biggest question is coming into this were,
我之前想要探索的问题是
how were the placement rates and what kind of salaries can we expect?
编程训练营是否会对就业和工资有影响
And the truth is that,
事实是
they're kind of widespread more than any other category.
这个类别比其他类比的比例要大得多
Most individuals had a job already
很多人在参加训练营前就已经有工作了
before doing the boot camp or while doing the boot camp.
或者在参加训练营期间就找到了工作
And so, it's hard to tell what influence that had on them.
所以很难体现 训练营对就业的影响
And then additionally, the salaries for those individuals are all over.
此外 工资的分布也都非常分散 没有显著的差异